David C. Provost

733 Leatherstone Lane Fuquay Varina, NC 27526 (774) 232-8522 dave@fourponds.net

Qualifications Summary

Advanced library paraprofessional and customer service specialist, with skill sets including ILL and document delivery, customer service, supervision of student workers and full-time employees, and project management. Broad experience across multiple fields, spanning an expanding range of duties and responsibilities, including demonstrated ability to manage individuals and generate results. Significant exposure to veterinary medicine and information technology. Able to interact at all levels of an organization.

Recent Work Experience

NC State University LibrariesRaleigh, NCUniversity Library Technician – Advanced2018 - PresentUniversity Library Technician2016 - 2018

Provide world-class service to all library patrons at one of the nation's premiere veterinary specialty libraries. Manage day-to-day operations, including Interlibrary Loan, document delivery requests, and course reserves. Hire, train and manage student workers and full-time employees.

NC State University Veterinary Hospital

Raleigh, NC 2014 – 2016

Business Office Specialist

Responsible for wide range of administrative duties within NC State Veterinary Hospital Business Office.

Provided excellent client service at specialty and emergency services, with flexibility and understanding to cover multiple services as needed.

NC State University Veterinary Hospital Pharmacy

Raleigh, NC

Inventory Manager

2010 - 2014

Provided inventory management services for world-class veterinary teaching hospital pharmacy.

Completed projects using Lean Healthcare methodologies to increase efficiency and provide cost savings throughout the pharmacy and the hospital.

Cape Animal Referral and Emergency Center

South Dennis, MA

2007 - 2008

Interim Hospital Manager

Client Service Manager

Client Service Representative

Promoted to senior management position at Cape Cod's only 24-hour emergency and referral veterinary hospital.

Developed and implemented hospital-wide policies and procedures.

Google, Inc. (via WorkforceLogic)

Quality Rater

Remote

Self-motivated, part-time quality rater for Google search properties.

Completed a variety of tasks and projects as assigned.

2006 - 2007

Education

University of North Carolina at Greensboro, Greensboro, NC

Part-time MLIS candidate. Expected graduation in 2022.

Simmons University, Boston, MA

MLIS coursework taken in 2007 at Graduate School of Library and Information Sciences.

University of Vermont, Burlington, VT

Graduated in 2001 with Master of Science degree in Historic Preservation. GPA 4.00

Tufts University, Medford, MA

Graduated Magna Cum Laude in 1998 with Bachelor of Arts degree in Art History. GPA 3.77

Additional post-graduate classwork and training

Accounting and Economics at University of Massachusetts, Boston Lean Healthcare 100H and 200H through NCSU Industrial Extension Service

Other Interests and Achievements

Volunteer; NC State Libraries Student Appreciation Program Committee	2018-Present
Winner, NC State Pride of the Wolfpack Award	2018
Quizmaster; GWD, LLC	2017-Present
Volunteer; Dillard Drive Elementary School and Moore Square Middle School Libraries	2010-2015
Trustee; The Laurel School (Brewster MA)	2007-2009
Presenter; Vermont Historic Preservation Conference, "Accessibility for Historic Buildings: A Field Guide"	2001
Winner; Tufts University History of Art Prize	1998